A Guide to the Papers of the Carter and Wellford Family of Sabine Hall 1650-1918
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series VI: Correspondence of Armistead Nelson Wilford
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1867 February 22 (Box-folder 3:18)
    "stag laws" negative effect on collectors; impending judgments; comment on present legislature and the effects of reconstruction laws, including the repudiation law
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1867 June 18 (Box-folder 3:18)
    collection of debts owed to the Carter estate; insolvent condition of the White Sulphur Springs Company
  - Edward Thornton Tayloe to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1867 June (Box-folder 3:18)
    in debt to the executors and the estate
  - Edward Thornton Tayloe to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1867 July 8 (Box-folder 3:18)
    opportunity to draw Kate's interest on Virginia Stock; disfranchised under General Schofield's Order; pardoned by the President; seeks assistance for this dilemma from Judge William Wood Crump; monument in memory of lost soldiers; contrabands outnumber in Hampton District; hostility toward Congress
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1867 August 10 (Box-folder 3:18)
    letter from Alexander Tayloe demanding interest on bonds of Col. Carter; response to the demand; confer with Maury and Capterton; debts owed to the Carter estate; John Seddon's land
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1867 August 22 (Box-folder 3:18)
    draft from E. C. Marshall
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1867 August 26 (Box-folder 3:18)
    arrangements with one of the debtors
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1867 August 31 (Box-folder 3:18)
    various judgments for interest; unproductive to serve judgment against certain debtors
  - Edward Thornton Tayloe to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1867 September 16 (Box-folder 3:18)
    arrival of Kate Carter at Powhatan Hill
  - Edward Thornton Tayloe to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1867 November 7 (Box-folder 3:18)
    Kate's request for money weekly; interest due her; certificates of stock
  - Edward Thornton Tayloe to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1867 November (Box-folder 3:18)
    Kate's January dividend; contact the auditor for the certificates for the arrears of interest not paid on the State Stock
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1867 November 15 (Box-folder 3:18)
    William Henry Tayloe ready to settle debt of Newman
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford, with letter from F. B. Miller, January 8 1868 January 17 (Box-folder 3:19)
    unproductive to serve judgment against certain debtors assumed character of Mr. May; demoralization of the times; Miller to foreclose the deed of trust; broken promises to pay interest on debts; suits against some of the debtors; regret in being appointed by the Conservative Convention to the Consulting Committee of the District; thoughts on the proceedings of the Convention; scheme of organization too complex; harsh comments on the radicals pushing for the black vote; negative opinion on the future of the government; lengthy discourse of his fears and opinions of what black civil rights would bring; "diabolical scheme of radical policy" to secure the presidential election with the black vote
  - Edward Thornton Tayloe to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1868 January 21 (Box-folder 3:19)
    trustees account; Kate's debt; the France accounts
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford, with letter from F. B. Miller, January 28 1868 February 14 (Box-folder 3:19)
    meeting with ladies who are the legatees under the will of Dr. Hooe; debts owed to the Carter estate; May debt; decision on best course to pursue; theatre of operations so far away; judgments on debtors; organized to battle the radicals in the spring; promise to do everything to save the Commonwealth
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford, with letter from F. B. Miller, February 17 1868 February 26 (Box-folder 3:19)
    War debt owed to the Carter estate; Congressional Convention's rejection of repudiation or scaling of debts
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1868 February 26 (Box-folder 3:19)
    advice on handling the bankruptcy of Ward; consultation with Beverley R. Wellford on the Morgan case; debts owed to the Carter estate
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford, with letter from F. B. Miller, March 2 1868 March 11 (Box-folder 3:19)
    Beverley R. Wellford to attend to the interests of the estate; debts owed to the Carter estate; enclosed letter from Beverley R. Wellford concerning the Morgan case
  - Edward Thornton Tayloe to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1868 March 17 (Box-folder 3:19)
    statement of debts paid through Dr. Beverley R. Wellford; Kate's debts to Wellford
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1868 March 18 (Box-folder 3:19)
    location of the Mays bond; questions of antagonistic interests between the legatees; suggests that Beverley R. Wellford attend to this matter; General Schofield has suspended proceedings under deeds of trust
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1868 April 8 (Box-folder 3:19)
    Miller's debt; enclosed letter from Miller; possible consent to an estate sale for cash
  - Edward Thornton Tayloe to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1868 April 9 (Box-folder 3:19)
    Kate's request for money; family news
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1868 May 11 (Box-folder 3:20)
    urged payment of the interest on Caperton's note
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1868 May 28 (Box-folder 3:20)
    H. A. Risley's payment of interest on the Kemper account; news that Tom Jones conveyed all of his property to his family to secure other creditors
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1868 June 16 (Box-folder 3:20)
    propositions from S. A. J. Salter, John Carnell and F. B. Miller concerning their respective tracts
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1868 June 18 (Box-folder 3:20)
    advertisement of the May's land; May's intention to avail himself of the bankrupt act
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1868 July 18 (Box-folder 3:20)
    advises attendance to the sale of the May's land; proposal of involuntary bankruptcy to Tom Jones and advice against this action; E. C. Marhsall's debt
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1868 July 21 (Box-folder 3:20)
    request to Miller to postpone the sale of May's land due to a conflict with the election
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1868 July 27 (Box-folder 3:20)
    discussion of May's bankruptcy
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1868 July 30 (Box-folder 3:20)
    request to Garland to pay his bonds to R. W. Carter
  - F. B. Miller to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1868 August 10 (Box-folder 3:20)
    proposals set before Wellford; Mays case to go in front of Court of Bankruptcy; assignees acquire legal title by the deed of assignment
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1868 August 11 (Box-folder 3:20)
    unclear as to the effects of May's bankruptcy on the sale of his land; letter from F. B. Miller
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1868 August 14 (Box-folder 3:20)
    opinions on the bankrupt law; difficulties explained by Miller
  - Beverley R. Wellford to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1868 August 18 (Box-folder 3:20)
    Mays' bankruptcy should not interfere with the sale under the trust bond; six months before the adjudication of the bankruptcy; assignee in bankruptcy elected by creditors; in interest of the estate to facilitate the proceedings in bankruptcy
  - F. B. Miller to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1868 August 19 (Box-folder 3:20)
    sale of Mr. Mays' property; consulted with Judge William David Cole of the Court of Appeals
  - Armistead Nelson Wellford to Beverley R. Wellford 1868 September 4 (Box-folder 3:20)
    saw Mr. Scott, president of the Bank of Commerce in Fredericksburg; examination of the transfer book revealed several transfers six months prior to Carter's sale to Mays
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1868 September 26 (Box-folder 3:20)
    report and account of Carter's executors to Mr. Chew; personal property transferred to Wellford as guardian of his son, Carter; discussion of charging the expenses and profits of the land to his ward; inquiry as to his commission
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1868 November 6 (Box-folder 3:20)
    Col. Tayloe's approval in relation to borrowing money to discharge the bonds; Tyler's debt; advises to borrow sufficient funds to pay off the whole debt owed to Gordon
  - William Daniel, Jr. to [ ] 1868 November 27 (Box-folder 3:20)
    Col. Allen stated that the estate of Mr. Mays was turned over to the assignees; Col. Allen does not feel authorized to take further steps in the case
  - Allen Taylor Caperton to George W. Lewis 1868 December 9 (Box-folder 3:20)
    payment depends on the result of a negotiation
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1869 January 27 (Box-folder 3:21)
    payment of James Marshall on his bond and J. C. Mays' debt
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1869 February 8 (Box-folder 3:21)
    called as witness to the prosecution in the Postmistress at Oak vs. C. C. Jett; Mays' draft
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1869 February 20 (Box-folder 3:21)
    clerk recorded the executorial account
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1869 March 10 (Box-folder 3:21)
    action concerning the Missouri bonds; the Gordon suit; discounted debts
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1869 April 24 (Box-folder 3:21)
    "obstinate inaction and paralysis in public affairs"; Wallace and Coleman debts; Lemoine suit; Dr. Mays' draft; wish to dispose of the Warsaw City property; Missouri bonds; all court business suspended; possible loss on the Lee debt; William Little defense in suit against the Seddon estate
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1869 May 10 (Box-folder 3:21)
    draft of Dr. Mays to be paid; incidental expenses; Council in Fredericksburg
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1869 August 17 (Box-folder 3:21)
    bankruptcy of Fletcher H. Mays; question of usury in the sale of the Bank of Commerce stock to Mays; Judge Raleigh Travers Daniel
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1869 August 18 (Box-folder 3:21)
    served by the Circuit Court of Richmond on Figgatt vs. Williams assignees of Fletcher M. Mays in banktruptcy; B. T. Johnson solicitor for complainant; charge of usury; Beverley R. Wellford and Judge William Daniel to assist in such proceedings; need to prove if stock was a sale or a loan; wishes to retain Judge Joynes of the Court of Appeals and Christian (Joynes, Christian and Joynes)
  - Beverley R. Wellford to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1869 August 19 (Box-folder 3:21)
    copy of the bill of Mays' assignees
  - Beverley R. Wellford to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1869 August 26 (Box-folder 3:21)
    power of attorney; Judge Richard Cassius Lee Moncure's award as to the interpretation of the will
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1869 September 4 (Box-folder 3:21)
    petition of Mays' against the Carter executors; Beverley R. Wellford familiar with the case; Judge Raleigh Travers Daniel
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1869 September 20 (Box-folder 3:21)
    case of Mays' assignees vs. Carter's executors; importance of the presence of Beverley R. Wellford; Judge Raleigh Travers Daniel
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1869 September 27 (Box-folder 3:21)
    important to attend "this dishonorable proceeding of May"; Judge R. C. L. Moncure's award on the construction of the will
  - George B. Scott to Beverley R. Wellford 1869 October 31 (Box-folder 3:21)
    information from the books of the Bank of Commerce concerning transactions between Carter and Mays
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1869 November 25 (Box-folder 3:21)
    personal and professional financial difficulties; suffering from neuralgia or rheumatism; plans for a meeting with Col. Tayloe. Armistead Nelson Wellford, and himself; Morgan debt; some of Belfield's bonds are insolvent
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1869 December 15 (Box-folder 3:21)
    judgment for costs in Carter executors vs. Morgan; suit terminated when a agreement was made between Morgan, his attorney, and himself; explanation and reasons for agreement
  - Edward Thornton Tayloe to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1869 December 30 (Box-folder 3:21)
    power of attorney to draw the dividends on Kate's [Catherine Carter's] stock
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1870 March 1 (Box-folder 4:1)
    proposal to adopt a course to raise the gold to meet the demands of Gold & Taylor; debts of Jones, Marshall and Kemper; Morgan property at Warsaw; Judge Moncure's charge for the arbitration case; case against Miss Carter
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford, with two letters from R. C. L. [Richard Cassius Lee] Moncure 1870 March 19 (Box-folder 4:1)
    Judge Moncure's fee as arbitrator; Risley and Marshall debts; explanation of the debt owed to Moncure and Barton
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford, with two letters, from James and Edward C. Marshall 1870 March 29 (Box-folder 4:1)
    no deed of trust on James Marshall's land to secure the debt; courses to take in collecting the debt; character of James Marshall as highly honorable and quite elderly; Edward C. Marshall's case is obstinate and chronic; may be compelled to resort to a sale under the deed; Kemper date to be paid in gold; election of judges; relates a "murder, arson & robbery marked by the most barbarous & atrocious circumstances" in the neighborhood of "Claymont"; actions blamed on the negroes; bitter feelings and threats to hang those guilty
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1870 March 30 (Box-folder 4:1)
    assumption of the Kemper debt by Col. H. A. Risley; arrangements to pay debt in silver; requirement of assignment before payment
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford, with note from Garland & Company 1870 April 5 (Box-folder 4:1)
    received the Morgan deed; advice from Beverley R. Wellford as to a suitable lawyer for the suits; own preference is James Neeson; death of Pendelton, the trustee, causing some impediment; Kemper bonds and Missouri bonds will enable the proper funds to be raised to discharge Col. Carter's liability to Gordon & Taylor; suggestion that all parties unite and raise the amount in greenbacks to pay the debt; to consult with Allen Taylor Caperton; debts of the Marshalls; old-fashioned ideas about judges; talk of himself nominated for county judge
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1870 April 23 (Box-folder 4:1)
    problem with procurement of silver by H. A. Riggs; Riggs is a gentleman and honorable man
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1870 April 29 (Box-folder 4:1)
    constitutionality of the legal tender notes was before the Supreme Court; Riggs attempt to secure silver; payment of portion of Judge Moncure's fee; Judge Herndon; authorized Beverly R. Wellford to engage the services of James Alfred Jones in the May case; Warsaw shop property
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1870 May 5 (Box-folder 4:1)
    pleasant visit with Kate Carter at Sabine Hall; appointment of W. A. Brockenbrough as clerk; payment of Lemaine debt by Capt. Harding
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1870 May 7 (Box-folder 4:1)
    large portion of Lemaine debt paid; awaiting word from Riggs
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford, with note from Riggs & Company 1870 May 11 (Box-folder 4:1)
    delay in payment from H. A. Risley
  - Edward Thornton Tayloe to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1870 June 7 (Box-folder 4:2)
    circumstances of Kate in regard to money; White Sulphur Springs to advance greatly in value from the construction of the Chesapeake & Ohio Railroad
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford, with note from Allen Taylor Caperton 1870 June 11 (Box-folder 4:2)
    his account with the estate; suggests that James Alfred Jones take the depositions from Wellford and Miller
  - W. H. Fitzhugh to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1870 June 15 (Box-folder 4:2)
    wishes to apply for the settlement
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1870 September 5 (Box-folder 4:2)
    sale of the residue of the Missouri bonds; proposal to Gordon; Marshall, Risley and Jones debts; no personal property at Sabine Hall to levy; title transferred to Wellford, the guardian of Robert Carter Wellford
  - Edward Thornton Tayloe to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1870 September 20 (Box-folder 4:2)
    estate provisions for Kate; responsibility for supplying her needs; convention at Matthew's Court House to nominate a candidate for Congress
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1870 September 30 (Box-folder 4:2)
    no word from Risley; instructed Lawrence B. Taylor, trustee to proceed with the sale of "Clifton" to pay the debt
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1870 October 13 (Box-folder 4:2)
    insurance paid on the house; Wellford elected as a member of the Board of Vickers of William and Mary College
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1870 December 19 (Box-folder 4:2)
    deed of trust from Morgan to Pendleton; Mr. Sydnor wishes to purchase portion of the property; Kemper and Marshall debts; deposits made by H. A Risley
  - William Daniel, Jr. to James Alfred Jones 1870 December 29 (Box-folder 4:2)
    examined the answer he proposes to file in the case of Carter vs. Mays
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1870 December 30 (Box-folder 4:2)
    Kemper debt paid through Riggs and Company
  - James Pleasants to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1871 February 14 (Box-folder 4:3)
    D. H. Gordon's debts against White Sulphur Springs; payments received from D. H. Gordon, Allen Taylor Caperton, Gen. F. H. Smith, Philip St. George Cocke
  - James Pleasants to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1871 March 6 (Box-folder 4:3)
    receipt to Wellford for payment to D. H. Gordon by the White Sulphur Springs obligors; several accounts as guardian of Robert Carter Wellford and executor of the estate of Robert Wormeley Carter
  - William L. Clark to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1871 April 1 (Box-folder 4:3)
    mortgage on property
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford, with letters from William L. Waring 1871 May 8 (Box-folder 4:3)
    debt to the Carter executors by Thomas R. and Lawson Waring; proposals to clear debt; visit to Tappahannock by W. L. Waring and Robert Baylor; R. M. T. (Robert Mercer Taliaferro) Hunter; the Warings and R. M. T. Hunter protect their property from creditors when drawn to deeds of trust and settlements; accuses these "most trusted & worthy men a great relaxation of morals"; deed of trust from Robert Waring; delinquent debt of E. C. Marshall; W. L. Waring not willing to make a confession of judgment
  - William L. Clark to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1871 May 27 (Box-folder 4:3)
    Mr. Llewelyn's payment and intent
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1871 June 15 (Box-folder 4:3)
    John M. Carty qualified as township clerk; value of a certain property will be decreased if the Shaw house is not included
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford, with letter from Bradley T. Johnson 1871 June 22 (Box-folder 4:3)
    Bradley T. Johnson's propositions of compromise to Judge Beverley Randolph Wellford; objections to the propositions
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1871 July 4 (Box-folder 4:3)
    account of Mr. Little for publishing circular notices of the change of the courts
  - William L. Waring to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1871 July 5 (Box-folder 4:3)
    anxious for settlement of the claim due by the Waring brothers; suggests proposition; claims they hold against Col. Tayloe
  - J. M. Herndon to Armistead Nelson Wellfor 1871 July 21 (Box-folder 4:3)
    explanation of payment distribution of Wellford's check
  - J. M. Herndon to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1871 July 27 (Box-folder 4:3)
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1871 August 26 (Box-folder 4:3)
    agreement to the terms proposed by Mr. Figgat
  - Edward Thornton Tayloe to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1871 (Box-folder 4:3)
    Kate's July remittance; corn crop
  - John A. Carter to George W. Lewis 1872 June 8 (Box-folder 4:4)
    arrangement of debt of Edward C. Marshall; Jacqueline A. Marshall and John T. Grant subsequent purchasers of the land; united deed of trust and bonds
  - Edward Thornton Tayloe to Armistead Nelson Wellford, with sketch of soundings off Tappahannock 1872 August 12 (Box-folder 4:4)
    enclosing sketch of the chart with the soundings off Tappahannock; corn and wheat crops and prices; election of Critcher, Montague and Braxton for judge
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1872 October 10 (Box-folder 4:4)
    conversations with Allen Taylor Braxton about his proposition concerning his debt; Braxton's transactions
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford, with letter from Col. William Gordon 1872 December 5 (Box-folder 4:4)
    rejection of Waring's and Gordon's proposal; award of Richard Cassius Lee Moncure; debt of Allen Taylor Caperton
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford, with letter from J. A. Carter 1873 January 8 (Box-folder 4:4)
    receipt of check from Warings; proposal from Carter
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1873 January 18 (Box-folder 4:4)
    Carter collected first payments due by D. A. Marshall and I. T. Grant; instructions to remit the money to Wellford; approve proposal pertaining to the Warings' debt; effort to settle with Allen T. Caperton
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1873 February 11 (Box-folder 4:4)
    order on Col. McDonald; roads bad from Sabine Hall; unusual accident where a ferry was hit by a steam boat which was "a cold act of impudence that none but a Yankee would have been guilty of"; deteriorating condition of the ferry and the rope; judiciary question before the General Assembly
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford, with note from John A. Carter 1873 June 28 (Box-folder 4:4)
    Carter's request to hold the previous check
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1873 May 10 (Box-folder 4:4)
    proposition from Allen Taylor Caperton; Caperton's claim against the Chesapeake & Ohio Railroad Company; problem with the Warings and their debt; Col. Gordon's assistance; Mr. Figgat's delay in writing; business with Mr. Nevitt; prosecutions against Burk Stuart ended in his favor; fishing cases of James and Frank Stuart; request him to consult with Col. McDonald and get copies of Grattan's Reports
  - Edward Thornton Tayloe to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1873 June 11 (Box-folder 4:4)
    nomination of Dr. Armistead; Whig and Radical parties; "colored gentry may elect" a popular man, if found by the Radicals
  - George W. Lewis to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1873 June 25 (Box-folder 4:4)
    check from J. A. Carter; general meeting of the alumni of the University of Virginia on July 1st; request to Judge James Mercer Garnett to delay court date; Wellford's nomination to the Senate; caution among the politicians; districts in the State; choice of leaders should be for their capacity and qualifications; Robert Hall has declared himself a candidate; prejudices often enter into making decisions; J. D. Rodgers anxious for the position; radical party strong in the Northern Neck
  - Edward Thornton Tayloe to Armistead Nelson Wellford 1873 June (Box-folder 4:4)